Register of the T. V. (Tzu-wen) Soong papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence [Chinese language], 1942-1947
  - Kuang tung lü Kuei t'ung hsiang hui, 1946
    Box/Folder 38: 49
  - Kuo, K'ai-chi, 1943
    Box/Folder 38: 50
  - Kuomintang, Central Committee, 1947
    Box/Folder 38: 51
  - Leng, Yü, 1945
    Box/Folder 38: 52
  - Li, Shu-p'ing, 1945
    Box/Folder 38: 53
  - Li, Shun-ch'iao, undated
    Box/Folder 38: 54
  - Li, Te-chieh, 1943
    Box/Folder 38: 55
  - Li, Yu-ying, 1947
    Box/Folder 38: 56
  - Liu, Kung-yün, undated
    Box/Folder 38: 57
  - Liu, Pao-ch'en, 1946
    Box/Folder 38: 58
  - Liu, Wen-tao, 1946
    Box/Folder 38: 59
  - Lu, Han, 1945
    Box/Folder 39: 1
  - Ma, Ch'ao-chün, 1945
    Box/Folder 39: 2
  - Mo, Liu-sen, undated
    Box/Folder 39: 3
  - Pei-p'ing shih fan ta hsüeh (Lung-nan), T'ung hsüeh hui, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 4
  - Po-ch'iang tieh shih yen chiu so ch'ou pei wei yüan hui, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 5
  - San-min-chu-i Youth Corps, 1943
    Box/Folder 39: 6
  - Sun, Peng-jung, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 7
  - Tai, Chi-t'ao, 1942
    Box/Folder 39: 8
  - T'ang Tsu-i, 1946?
    Box/Folder 39: 9
  - Tseng, Kung-le, 1947
    Box/Folder 39: 10
  - Tseng, Ming, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 11
  - Tsu, Ting-wen, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 12
  - Tu, Hou-ch'ing, Mrs., 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 13
  - Wan, Kuo-ping, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 14
  - Wang, Chün-wei, 1946?
    Box/Folder 39: 15
  - Wang, Hsin-heng, 1946?
    Box/Folder 39: 16
  - Wang, Shou-p'eng, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 17
  - Wang, Yen-shun, 1945
    Box/Folder 39: 18
  - Wen, Ch'en-lieh, 1945
    Box/Folder 39: 19
  - Weng, Wen-hao, 1945?
    Box/Folder 39: 20
  - Wu, Han-chen, 1945?
    Box/Folder 39: 21
  - Wu, Shih-chiao, 1945
    Box/Folder 39: 22
  - Yang Min Yuan, 1947
    Box/Folder 39: 23
  - Yang, Sen, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 24
  - Yin, Chung-jung, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 25
  - Yü, Hsüeh-chung, 1946
    Box/Folder 39: 26
- Telegrams [Chinese language], 1937, 1940-1944
  Telegrams sent and received, arranged chronologically. Security-classified telegrams were removed and are now available in Formerly Closed Material [Chinese language].
  - Incoming
    - 1937 (Reel 49)
      Box/Folder 39: 27
    - 1940-1941
      Box/Folder 39: 28-32
  - Outgoing, 1940 December - 1941 December, 1942 January, April - October, 1943 February - September (Reel 50)
    Box/Folder 41: 1-2
  - Outgoing, 1941 August-December
    Box/Folder 41: 3-4
  - Incoming, 1942 January-April (Reel 51)
    Box/Folder 41: 5-6
  - Outgoing, 1942 January, April-June
    Box/Folder 41: 7
  - Outgoing (cont'd.), 1942 January, April-June
    Box/Folder 42: 1
  - Incoming, 1942 May-December
    Box/Folder 42: 2
  - Background of 1943 apology letter to Chaing Kai-shek (Reel 52)
    Box/Folder 42: 3
  - Outgoing, 1942 July - 1943 September
    Box/Folder 42: 4-6
  - Incoming, 1943 February-September
    Box/Folder 42: 7
  - Miscellany, 1943 October - 1944 December
    Box/Folder 43: 1-2
  - Miscellany, 1943 October - 1944 December (Reel 53)
    Box/Folder 43: 3-5
- Subject File [Chinese language], 1937-1946
  Documents of associations, interviews, memoranda, printed material, and reports, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Agriculture, Russia
    Box/Folder 43: 6
  - Chiang, Po-li
    Box/Folder 43: 7
  - China
    - Air Force, American Volunteer Group
      Box/Folder 43: 8
    - Coal mining
      Box/Folder 43: 9
    - Commerce
      Box/Folder 43: 10
    - Communism
      Box/Folder 43: 11
    - Cooperation
      Box/Folder 43: 12
    - Currency question
      Box/Folder 43: 13
    - Han's family (Reel 54)
      Box/Folder 44: 1-2
    - Irrigation machine
      Box/Folder 44: 3
    - Job applications and resumes, 1945-1946
      Box/Folder 44: 4
    - Manchuria
      Box/Folder 44: 5
    - Nanking, pictorial works
      Box/Folder 44: 6
    - National Resources Commission
      Box/Folder 44: 7
    - Politics and policy
      Box/Folder 44: 8
    - Reconstruction
      Box/Folder 44: 9
    - Rice, supply and price
      Box/Folder 44: 10
    - Shanghai - Customs Office
      Box/Folder 44: 11
    - Sino-Japanese Conflict (1937-1945)
      Box/Folder 44: 12
    - Sun Yat-sen's will
      Box/Folder 44: 13
    - Textile industry
      Box/Folder 44: 14
    - Yeh, Ch'u-ts'ang, 1946
      Box/Folder 44: 15
  - Chinese folk-tale
    Box/Folder 44: 16
  - Economics
    Box/Folder 44: 17
  - Food supply
    Box/Folder 44: 18
  - Tobacco industry (Reel 55)
    Box/Folder 44: 19
  - U.S.
    - Commerce
      Box/Folder 44: 20
    - Foreign relations
      Box/Folder 44: 21
- Formerly Closed Material [Chinese language], 1940-1948
  Formerly security-classified documents and restricted material, including correspondence of Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek and Madame Mei-ling Soong Chiang and name lists of officials, now open.
  - Telegrams (formerly security-classified, now open)
    - Chronological file, 1940-1947
      - Incoming, 1940 August-October
        Box/Folder 45: 1
      - Outgoing, 1940 July-November
        Box/Folder 45: 2-3
      - Incoming, 1941 January-December
        Box/Folder 45: 4-5
      - Incoming, 1941 January-December (Reel 56)
        Box/Folder 45: 6
      - Incoming, 1942 January-April
        Box/Folder 45: 7-8
      - Incoming, 1942 May-October
        Box/Folder 45: 9-11
      - Outgoing, 1942 April-October and 1943
        Box/Folder 45: 12
      - 1943 January-September
        Box/Folder 46: 1
      - 1943 January-September (Reel 57)
        Box/Folder 46: 2-3
      - 1943 October - 1944 December
        Box/Folder 46: 4-6
      - 1945 January-March
        Box/Folder 46: 7
      - Incoming, 1945 April-December (Reel 58)
        Box/Folder 46: 8
      - Incoming (cont'd.), 1945 April-December
        Box/Folder 47: 1-4
      - Incoming (cont'd.), 1945 April-December (Reel 59)
        Box/Folder 47: 5-6
      - Incoming, 1945 July - 1946 May
        Box/Folder 47: 7-9
      - Incoming (cont'd.), 1945 July - 1946 May (Reel 60)
        Box/Folder 48: 1-5
      - Incoming (cont'd.), 1945 July - 1946 May (Reel 61)
        Box/Folder 48: 6-7
      - Incoming, 1946 May - 1947 April
        Box/Folder 48: 8-9
      - Incoming (cont'd.), 1946 May - 1947 April
        Box/Folder 49: 1
      - Outgoing, 1945 January-March
        Box/Folder 49: 2
      - Outgoing, 1945 October - 1946 January
        Box/Folder 49: 3-4
      - Outgoing, 1945 January, March, October, November and 1947 February (Reel 62)
        Box/Folder 49: 5-7
    - Alphabetical file, 1945-1946
      - Chang, Chih-ch'in, 1946
        Box/Folder 49: 8
      - Chang, Kung ch'üan, 1946
        Box/Folder 49: 9
      - Ch'en, Ch'eng, 1946
        Box/Folder 49: 10
      - Ch'en, I, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 49: 11
      - Ch'en, Kung-ch'ia, 1946
        Box/Folder 49: 12
      - Ch'eng, I-fa, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 49: 13
      - Chiang, Meng-lin, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 1
      - Chiang, Shao, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 2
      - Chiang, Wei-hsien, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 50: 3
      - Ch'ien, I-li, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 4
      - Ch'ien, Ta-chün, 1945
        Box/Folder 50: 5
      - Chu, Shih-ming, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 6
      - Fang, Chao-kao, 1946 (Reel 63)
        Box/Folder 50: 7
      - Ho, Ying-ch'ing, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 50: 8
      - Hsü, Hsüeh-yü, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 50: 9-11
      - Hsü, Le-t'ien, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 50: 12
      - Lin, Chi-yung, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 13
      - Liu, Hung-sheng, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 50: 14
      - Liu, Kung-yün, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 50: 15
      - Mo, Heng, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 16
      - Pei, Sung-sun, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 17
      - P'eng, Shih-nien, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 18
      - P'eng, Hsüeh-p'ei, 1946
        Box/Folder 50: 19
      - P'eng, Hsüeh-p'ei, 1946 (Reel 64)
        Box/Folder 50: 20
      - P'eng, Hsüeh-p'ei (cont'd.), 1946
        Box/Folder 51: 1-2
      - Shu, Yün-chang, 1946
        Box/Folder 51: 3
      - Sun, Li-jen, 1946
        Box/Folder 51: 4
      - Sun, Yueh-ch'i, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 51: 5
      - T'an, Po-yü, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 51: 6
      - Wang, Ch'ung-chih, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 51: 7
      - Wang, Shih-chieh, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 51: 8-9
      - Wang, Shou-ching, 1945-1946 (Reel 65)
        Box/Folder 51: 10-11
      - Wei, Tao-ming, 1946
        Box/Folder 51: 12
      - Weng, Yün-ni, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 51: 13
      - Yang, Kung-chao, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 51: 14
      - Yu, Hung-Chun (Yü, Fei-p'eng), 1946
        Box/Folder 51: 15
      - Yü, Hung-chün, 1945-1946
        Box/Folder 52: 1
  - Subject File (formerly security-classified material, now open), 1940-1948
    - Chang, Hsueh-liang
      Box/Folder 52: 2
    - China
      - Army
        Box/Folder 52: 3
      - Banks and banking
        Box/Folder 52: 4
      - Ching chi pu
        Box/Folder 52: 5
      - Committee on Wartime Planning for Chinese Students in the U.S.
        Box/Folder 52: 6
      - Communism, 1946
        Box/Folder 52: 7
      - Customs Office - personnel
        Box/Folder 52: 8
      - Finance
        Box/Folder 52: 9
      - Foreign relations - Soviet Union
        - General
          Box/Folder 52: 10-11
        - Treaty of Friendship and Alliance (Reel 66)
          Box/Folder 52: 12-13
      - Kuo min ta hui
        Box/Folder 52: 14
      - National Resources Commission
        Box/Folder 52: 15
      - Politics and government
        Box/Folder 52: 16
      - Rice merchants
        Box/Folder 52: 17
    - China Defense Supplies, Incorporated
      - Communications
        Box/Folder 52: 18-19
      - Requisition files for lend-lease supplies
        Box/Folder 53: 1
    - China Development Finance Corporation
      Box/Folder 53: 2
    - Chinese Supply Commission
      Box/Folder 53: 3
    - Cotton yarn supply
      Box/Folder 53: 4
    - The Fu Chung Corporation
      Box/Folder 53: 5
    - International Peace Campaign - China Branch (Reel 67)
      Box/Folder 53: 6-7
    - Japan - finance
      Box/Folder 53: 8
    - Kowloon City Wall Incident (Canton), 1948 January
      Box/Folder 53: 9
    - Kowloon City Wall Incident and Shameen outrage, 1948
      Box/Folder 53: 10-11
    - Kowloon City Wall Incident and Shameen outrage (cont'd.), 1948 (Reel 68)
      Box/Folder 54: 1-5
    - Kuomintang - Central Committee
      Box/Folder 54: 6
    - Lend-lease operation, 1941-1942 (Reel 69)
      Box/Folder 54: 7-8
    - Manchuria, 1945
      Box/Folder 54: 9
    - Sino-American Cooperation Organization (SACO)
      Box/Folder 54: 10
    - Sino-Japanese Conflict (1937-1945) - confiscations (Shanghai, Wuhan)
      Box/Folder 54: 11
    - Sino-Japanese Conflict (1937-1945) - confiscations (Shanghai, Wuhan) (cont'd.)
      Box/Folder 55: 1-5
    - Sino-Japanese Conflict (1937-1945) - confiscations (Shanghai, Wuhan) (cont'd.) (Reel 70)
      Box/Folder 56: 1-3
    - Student movement - Shanghai
      Box/Folder 56: 4
    - Tai, Li
      Box/Folder 56: 5
    - Transportation - Asia, Southeastern
      Box/Folder 56: 6
    - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1946
      Box/Folder 56: 7
    - World War (1937-1945)
      Box/Folder 56: 8
    - Wu, Ch'i-ting (corruption case)
      Box/Folder 56: 9
    - Yangtze Development Corporation
      Box/Folder 56: 10
  - Restricted material (now open)
    - Madame M. L. Soong Chiang
      Box/Folder 56: 11
    - China - foreign relations - Soviet Union, Mongolia
      Box/Folder 56: 12
    - World War (1937-1945) - Burma Road
      Box/Folder 56: 13
    - China - taxation, 1929-1932
      Box/Folder 56: 14
    - U.S. military supply to China
      Box/Folder 56: 15
    - Mahatma Gandhi in China with Chiang Kai-shek
      Box/Folder 56: 16
    - Chiang Kai-shek RSVP to Joseph Stilwell
      Box/Folder 56: 17
    - Chiang Kai-shek message to Joseph Stilwell, 1943 May (Reel 71)
      Box/Folder 57: 1
    - Kowloon city wall Incident, 1948 May
      Box/Folder 57: 2
    - General George Marshall and Chiang Kai-shek, 1945 September
      Box/Folder 57: 3
    - T. V. Soong to Chiang Kai-shek
      - 1945
        Box/Folder 57: 4
      - 1945 April 18-June 14
        Box/Folder 57: 5
    - Telegrams, Chiang Kai-shek
      Box/Folder 57: 6-7
    - China official name list
      Box/Folder 57: 8
    - Tai Li, correspondence, undated
      Box/Folder 57: 9
    - Telegrams (originals and copies) relating to T. V. Soong's visit to the Soviet Union, 1945 June
      Box/Folder 57: 10
    - Telegrams (originals and copies) relating to T. V. Soong's visit to the Soviet Union, 1945 June (Reel 72)
      Box/Folder 57: 11
    - Chiang Kai-shek in Mukden confronting Chinese Communist Party, 1945-1946
      Box/Folder 57: 12
- Photographs
  8 albums and 2 envelopes.
  - 1 photo album illustrating the work of the National Flood Relief Commission, 1931-1932 (Album fA)
  - 1 photo album of T. V. Soong on his return to China from the International Monetary and Economic Conference, 1933 (Album fB)
  - 1 photo album showing the results of General Sun Tien-ying's revolt against the Nanking Government, 1934 May (Album fC)
  - 1 photo album showing forestry, fishery, and agricultural activity on the island of Hai-nan, 1937 (Album fD)
  - 13 prints of T. V. Soong with Lord Halifax, Edward R. Stettinius, Vyacheslav Molotov, Henry Morgenthau Jr., Stanley K. Hornbeck, Henry L. Stimson, James V. Forrestal, President Harry S. Truman, and others (Envelope E)
    Includes two prints of Mrs. T. V. Soong and 33 from returned albums.
  - 2 prints, including one of T. V. Soong and group print of T. V. Soong, President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Winston Churchill, and others (Envelope mF)
  - 1 album of Chinese army personnel (Album fG)
  - 1 album of Chinese and allied officials and scenes in China during the World War II period (Album fH)
  - 1 album of battlefront scenes, circa 1937 (Album fI)
  - 1 album of prints of scenes of Kwangtung Province and of T. V. Soong as governor, 1947 (Album fJ)
- Microfilm, undated (Microfilm-cabinet cabinet)
  1 reel of scrapbooks and photo albums.
- Memorabilia, undated (Memorabilia cabinet)
  Relief portrait of Chinese man, possibly T. V. Soong.
- Oversize Materials, 1920-1945
  Charts, maps, and reports. For other oversize material, see box 65.
  - 28 maps of China, Southeast Asia, Russia, etc., primarily during World War II (Reel 50)
    Box 40
  - Report on foreign affairs by Tai Ch'i-tao for the Central Political Council, 1920 November 28
  - Report by the War Area Service Corps, National Military Council, China, "A Graphic Report of Thirty-Two Months' Service, July, 1942 - February, 1945, to the USAF Personnel in China"
  - 6 graphs on the finances of the Kuomintang government, 1940-1945
  - House plan
- Telegrams to and from Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek, 1940-1947
  - Chinese
    - Undated (Reel 72)
      Box/Folder 58: 1
    - 1940 June-October
      Box/Folder 58: 2
    - 1940 November-December
      Box/Folder 58: 3
    - 1941 January
      Box/Folder 58: 4
    - 1941 February
      Box/Folder 58: 5
    - 1941 March
      Box/Folder 58: 6
    - 1941 April
      Box/Folder 58: 7
    - 1941 May
      Box/Folder 58: 8
    - 1941 June
      Box/Folder 58: 9
    - 1941 July
      Box/Folder 58: 10
    - 1941 August
      Box/Folder 58: 11
    - 1941 September
      Box/Folder 58: 12
    - 1941 October
      Box/Folder 58: 13
    - 1941 November
      Box/Folder 58: 14
    - 1941 December (Reel 73)
      Box/Folder 58: 15
    - 1942 January
      Box/Folder 58: 16
    - 1942 February-March
      Box/Folder 58: 17
    - 1942 April
      Box/Folder 58: 18
    - 1942 May
      Box/Folder 58: 19
    - 1942 June
      Box/Folder 58: 20
    - 1942 July
      Box/Folder 59: 1
    - 1942 August
      Box/Folder 59: 2
    - 1942 September-December
      Box/Folder 59: 3
    - 1943 January-March
      Box/Folder 59: 4
    - 1943 April
      Box/Folder 59: 5
    - 1943 May
      Box/Folder 59: 6-9
    - 1943 June
      Box/Folder 59: 10
    - 1943 July
      Box/Folder 59: 11
    - 1943 August
      Box/Folder 59: 12-13
    - 1943 September
      Box/Folder 59: 14
    - 1947
      Box/Folder 59: 15
  - English
    - Undated
      Box/Folder 59: 16
    - 1940
      Box/Folder 59: 17
    - 1941
      Box/Folder 59: 18
    - 1942 (Reel 74)
      Box/Folder 59: 19
    - 1943
      Box/Folder 59: 20
- T. V. Soong's diary of Xi'an incident, 1936
  Box/Folder 59: 21
- Diary notes from meeting between T. V. Soong and Harry Hopkins, 1943 August 16
  Box/Folder 59: 22
- Joseph W. Stilwell files, 1942-1945
  Box/Folder 59: 23-24
- Joseph W. Stilwell files (cont'd.), 1942-1945
  Box/Folder 60: 1-4
- Claire Lee Chennault files, 1943-1949
  Box/Folder 60: 5-6
- Notes of T. V. Soong's meetings with John P. Davies, Harry Hopkins, Frank Knox, William Leahy, John J. McCloy, Frank Merrill, President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Joseph W. Stilwell, Henry L. Stimson, and Sumner Wells, Washington, D.C., 1943 May-June
  Box/Folder 60: 7
- Maps of China and Burma, referred to in the meeting notes at the White House, Washington, D.C., 1943 May-June, undated
  Box/Folder 60: 8
- George C. Marshall file, 1946
  Box/Folder 60: 9-10. Includes correspondence to S. C. Wang and Wei Tao-Ming. In Chinese and English.
- George C. Marshall file, 1946 (Reel 75)
  Box/Folder 60: 11-12. Includes correspondence to S. C. Wang and Wei Tao-Ming. In Chinese and English.
- Communist file - Chou En-lai, 1945-1946
  Box/Folder 60: 13. Includes report, "Directions of Anti-America Propaganda," edited by Bureau of Information, Laborer's Committee, Beijing, Chinese Communist Party, 1946 July 7.
- Kwangtung - Xiamen affairs file, 1948
  Box/Folder 60: 14-17
- Kwangtung - Xiamen affairs file (cont'd.), 1948
  Box/Folder 61: 1-5
- Biographical Material, 1968, undated
  - General, undated
    Box/Folder 61: 6
  - Biographical sketch in Biographical Dictionary of Republican China, Henry Boorman, with revisions by T. V. Soong, 1968 (Reel 76)
    Box/Folder 61: 7
  - "China's Alexander Hamilton," speech, Li Shu-fan, San Francisco, California, undated
    Box/Folder 61: 8
- Speeches, 1942-1949, undated
  - China Society Dinner, New York City, undated
    Box/Folder 61: 9. Typescript
  - University of California, undated
    Box/Folder 61: 10. Typescript
  - "Yale University Commencement,", 1942 June 9
    Box/Folder 61: 11. Typescript. Includes related materials
  - First Plenary Session of the United Nations Conference on International Organization, 1945 April 26
    Box/Folder 61: 12. Typescript
  - China-America Council of Commerce and Industry, 1945 June 4
    Box/Folder 61: 13. Typescript
  - "Governor Soong's Farewell Message to the People of Kwangtung,", 1949
    Box/Folder 61: 14. Typescript
- Correspondence, 1925, 1941-1971
  - Unidentified, undated
    Box/Folder 61: 15
  - American Banknote Company, 1942
    Box/Folder 61: 16
  - Arnold, H. H., 1942
    Box/Folder 61: 17
  - Bond, W. L., 1942
    Box/Folder 61: 18
  - Chennault, Claire Lee, 1942
    Box/Folder 61: 19
  - Corcoran, Tom, 1949-1956
    Box/Folder 61: 20
  - Dulles, John Foster, 1950
    Box/Folder 61: 21
  - Hopkins, Harry, 1941-1942
    Box/Folder 61: 22
  - Howard, Roy, 1940-1945
    Box/Folder 61: 23
  - King, P. Z., Robert Lim, and Ludwig Rajchman, 1941-1942
    Box/Folder 61: 24
  - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1950
    Box/Folder 61: 25. Includes testimony by T. V. Soong and H. H. K'ung in the United States Senate, 1950 May 10.
  - K'ung, H. H., 1941-1942
    Box/Folder 61: 26
  - Kuo, 1941
    Box/Folder 61: 27
  - Liao, General, 1925
    Box/Folder 61: 28
  - Lim, Robert. See: King, P. Z.
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr., 1941-1942
    Box/Folder 61: 29
  - Rajchman, Ludwig. See: King, P. Z.
  - Soong, Ching-ling (Madame Sun Yat-sen), 1942-1945
    Box/Folder 61: 30
  - Soong, Mei-ling (Madame Chiang Kai-shek), 1941-1971
    Box/Folder 61: 31
  - Soong, T. A., 1956-1962
    Box/Folder 61: 32
  - Sze, Alfred, 1943
    Box/Folder 61: 33
  - Sze, Sze-ming, 1942
    Box/Folder 61: 34
  - Truman, Harry, undated
    Box/Folder 61: 35
  - Wu, K. C., 1943
    Box/Folder 61: 36
- Chiang Kai-shek File, 1941-1945
  - Correspondence between Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek, Madame Chiang Kai-shek, and T. V. Soong
    - Undated
      Box/Folder 61: 37
    - 1941
      Box/Folder 61: 38
    - 1942
      Box/Folder 62: 1-3
    - 1943-1945 (Reel 77)
      Box/Folder 62: 4
  - Correspondence to and from Winston Churchill, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 62: 5
  - Correspondence to and from Franklin D. Roosevelt, 1942-1945
    Box/Folder 62: 6
  - Memoranda, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 62: 7
- Madame Chiang Kai-shek File, 1939-1943
  - General, 1942-1943
    Box/Folder 62: 8
  - War orphans file, 1939-1940
    Box/Folder 62: 9. Madame Chiang Kai-shek's letters to Charles Vickery, the Golden Rule Foundation; a letter from Madame Chiang Kai-shek to Boys and Girls Across the Ocean
  - Wellesley file, 1940-1941
    Box/Folder 62: 10
- Record of official incorporation of China Defense Supplies, Inc., 1941
  Box/Folder 62: 11
- Draft of Sino-Soviet treaty, 1945
  Box/Folder 62: 12. Includes an outline and related correspondence.
- Records relating to Sino-German relations, 1941
  Box/Folder 62: 13
- Diary notes, 1940-1950
  Box/Folder 62: 14. Notes from meeting between T. V. Soong and possibly Dean Acheson in Paris, after meeting with John Foster Dulles, 1949-1950; T. V. Soong's notes from meeting with John Foster Dulles, 1949 May 28; and intelligence reports, undated.
- Clippings, San Francisco Examiner, 1949
  Box/Folder 62: 15
- Financial Records, 1943-1999
  - Will and lists of personal financial assets; related financial records; clippings; decree settling first and final account of the last will and testament of T. V. Soong by William S. Youngman, Jr., executor, Surrogates Court, County of New York, 1943-1970, 1975, 1999
    Box/Folder 62: 16
  - Financial ledgers, 1963-1968
    Box/Folder 62: 17-18
  - Financial ledgers, 1963-1968 (Reel 78)
    Box/Folder 62: 19-21
- William S. Youngman's correspondence with Mr. and Mrs. Ivan Y. T. Feng, Sterling Seagrave, T. V. Soong; and Madame Chiang Kai-shek's letters to Michael Feng, 1946, 1984-1986
  Box/Folder 62: 22
- Photographs
  - 4 prints of Chinese student demonstrations at the British consulate (captions in Chinese on reverse), undated
    Box/Folder 62: 23
  - 1 print depicting President Harry Truman in the White House garden with Henry L. Stimson, James V. Forrestal, T. V. Soong, and Edward R. Stettinius, Jr., Washington, D.C., 1945 April 19
    Box/Folder 62: 24
- Moscow notes, 1950
  Box/Folder 63: 1
- Draft of the Soong/Stalin meeting minutes, 1945
  Box/Folder 63: 2
- Final draft of the Soong/Stalin meeting minutes, 1945
  Box/Folder 63: 3
- KMT-CCP Cooperation Agreement, 1950
  Box/Folder 63: 4
- Sino-Soviet Treaty, 1945
  - Meeting minutes, 1945
    Box/Folder 63: 5-8
  - English and Russian drafts, 1945
    Box/Folder 63: 9-10
  - English and Russian drafts, 1945 (Reel 79)
    Box/Folder 63: 11
  - Chinese draft, 1945
    Box/Folder 63: 12-14
  - Final draft, 1945
    Box/Folder 63: 15-17
  - Important documents, 1945
    Box/Folder 64: 1
  - Reference materials, 1945
    Box/Folder 64: 2-3. Includes treaties between the USSR and Czechoslovakia, Poland, United Kingdom, Yugoslavia, and France; Admiral Shen Hung-lieh's memo of Port Arthur, Chinese Eastern and South Manchurian Railways; and the treaty between China and Russia of 1896.
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1945
    Box/Folder 64: 4. Includes draft of principles governing the Sino-Soviet joint operation of the Chinese Eastern and South Manchurian Railways.
- Secret file, 1942-1945
  Box/Folder 64: 5-6
- Copies of documents which Hoover does not have originals
  Box/Folder 64: 7
- Material Opened in 2008, 1944
  - Memorandum concerning the politico-military situation in China, 1944 October 26